这是卡利托斯，你好。
There's Carlitos, hello.
Ahí está Carlitos, hola.
大家下午好。
Good afternoon to everyone.
Buen mediodía para todos.
欢迎来到阿根廷足球队教练莱昂内尔·埃斯卡隆的新闻发布会。
Welcome to the press conference of Lionel Escalón and coach of the Argentine Soccer Team.
Bienvenidos a la conferencia de prensa de Lionel Escalón y entrenador de la Selección Argentina de Fútbol.
我们还是像往常一样开始，今天人很少，所以请大家举手。
We are going to start as always, today there are few of us, so I ask you to raise your hand.
Vamos a comenzar como siempre, hoy somos pocos, así que les pido que me levanten la mano.
请麦克风。
Please, the microphone.
Por favor, el micrófono.
你看，我就是这样传递问题的。
to see, this is how I pass on the questions.
para ver, así les paso las preguntas.
让我们从这里开始吧。
Let's start there.
Vamos a arrancar allá.
等一下，莱安德罗。
Give me a second, Leandro.
Dame un segundo, Leandro.
请，22 号。
Please, number 22.
Por favor, número 22.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leónel, how are you doing?
Leónel, ¿cómo te va?
中午好。
Good mid-day.
Buen medio día.
好吧，问问自己他们如何面对周二的比赛，从根本上来说......
Well, ask yourself how they are facing Tuesday's game and fundamentally...
Bueno, preguntarte cómo están de cara al partido del martes y fundamentalmente...
亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特（Alexis McAllister）怎么样，尼科·冈萨雷斯（Nico González）怎么样，展望即将发生的事情。
How is Alexis McAllister, how is Nico González, looking ahead to what is coming.
cómo está Alexis McAllister, cómo está Nico González, de cara a lo que viene.
嗯，大家早上好，下午好。
Well, good morning everyone, good afternoon.
Bueno, buenas para todos, buen mediodía.
球队表现不错，从前几天的比赛中恢复了实力。
The team is doing well, regaining strength from the game the other day.
El equipo está bien, reponiendo fuerza del partido del otro día.
与一些典型的匹配轴。
with some typical match axes.
con algunos hachaques típicos del partido.
好吧，尼科经过训练并且与众不同，亚历克西斯
well, Nico trained and differentiated, Alexis
bueno, Nico entrenó y diferenciado, Alexis
我和我们一起训练。
I train with us.
Entreno con nosotros.
我们会看到进化是怎样的，并不是我们做了非常苛刻的训练。
We'll see how the evolution is, it's not that we did a very demanding training.
Ya veremos cómo es la evolución, tampoco es que hicimos un entrenamiento muy exigente.
让我们看看这些天的演变，然后再决定。
Let's see the evolution of these days to decide later.
Vamos a ver la evolución de estos días para decidir después.
我们将如何发挥，但总的来说我们很好。
how we are going to play, but in general we are good.
como vamos a jugar, pero en general estamos bien.
来自 Disportz 和 Dolamarilla 的 Fernando Sís，你好 Leonel。
Fernando Sís from Disportz and Dolamarilla, hello Leonel.
Fernando Sís de Disportz y Dolamarilla, hola Leonel.
第一个问题与...有关
The first question has to do with...
La primera pregunta tiene que ver con...
您和内斯托·罗德里格斯 (Néstor Rodríguez) 以及何塞·内斯托·佩克曼 (José Néstor Peckerman) 也加入其中。
You and Néstor Rodríguez are joined by José Néstor Peckerman.
A vos y a Néstor Rodríguez se los une José Néstor Peckerman.
我想问你怎么看。
I wanted to ask you how you see it.
Te quería preguntar cómo lo ves.
这是何塞职业生涯的最后阶段。
to José in this, which is the final stretch of his career.
a José en esto que es su recta final de su carrera.
考虑到您会为何塞找到什么地方
And what place would you find for José, taking into account
¿Y qué lugar vos le buscarías a José, teniendo en cuenta
自从他没有执导以来，他就陷入了这种僵局。
this impasse he has had since he didn't direct.
este impaz que tiene desde que no dirigió.
第二次是14日梅西再次为国际迈阿密队出场。
and the second is on the 14th Lionel Messi plays again for Inter Miami.
y la segunda es el 14 vuelve a jugar Lionel Messi para Inter Miami.
他回来后你要和他谈谈，看看你是否可以把他算进十月份。
You're going to talk to him after he returns to see if you can count him in for October.
Vas a hablar con él a posteriori de su regreso para ver si lo podés contar para octubre.
谢谢。
Gracias.
嗯，很久以前我和何塞在一起……嗯，当时……
Well, I was with José a long time ago... well, when it was...
Bueno, con José estuve hace... bueno, cuando fue el...
呃不幸的是
eh unfortunately the
eh lamentablemente el
那个瘦子和我们聊了一会儿。
the skinny one and we were talking for a while.
el flaco y estuvimos hablando un rato.
我们谈论足球 我们谈论什么
we talk about football we talk about what is
hablamos de fútbol hablamos de lo que está
发生了什么事，你的时间过得怎么样，对我们有好处
what's going on and how your time is going and good for us
lo que está pasando y cómo está pasando su momento y bueno para nosotros
我们希望看到他坐在替补席上，但我不知道他的想法是什么。
We would like to see him on a substitute bench, but I don't know what his idea is.
Nos gustaría verlo en algún banco de suplentes, pero no sé cuál es su idea.
显然，我们所有经过他手的人都被打上了某种印记。
It is evident that all of us who have passed through his hands have been marked in some way.
Es evidente que todos los que hemos pasado por sus manos de alguna manera quedamos marcados.
我希望我们能再次在替补席上看到他。
and I hope we can see him again on a substitute bench.
y ojalá lo podamos ver de nuevo en algún banco de suplentes.
至于利奥，我们希望他能上场，他开始上场。
And about Leo, well, we hope he plays, that he starts playing.
Y lo de Leo, bueno, esperamos que juegue, que empiece a jugar.
当我们必须像往常一样给出以下清单时，我们会与每个人进行沟通，他也不例外。
And when we have to give the following list, as we always do, we communicate with everyone and he will be no exception.
Y cuando tengamos que dar la siguiente lista, como siempre hacemos, nos comunicamos con todos y con él no será la excepción.
我们会等待那一天，我想......
We will wait for that day, which I think...
Esperaremos ese día, que creo que…
大约两周后，我们必须给出下一场比赛的名单，然后我们会看看它是否合适。
It will be in two weeks or so when we have to give the list for the next game and then we will see if it is fit.
será dentro de dos semanas más o menos cuando tenemos que dar la lista para el siguiente partido y ahí veremos si está en condiciones.
红色电台的 Gustavo Yarroch，我想问两个问题。
Gustavo Yarroch for Radio La Red, I want to ask two questions.
Gustavo Yarroch para Radio La Red, quiero hacer dos consultas.
如果你计划对周二的比赛进行多次或少量的修改，
If you plan to make many or few touch-ups thinking about Tuesday's game,
Si tenés previsto hacer muchos retoques o pocos pensando en el partido del martes,
在巴兰基亚和其他地方，趁着今天人少一些，我想向你咨询一下。
in Barranquilla and the other, taking advantage of the fact that there are a little less of us today, I want to consult you.
en Barranquilla y la otra aprovechando que somos un poco menos hoy, te quiero consultar.
如果您能告诉我您职业中的三个主要推荐人是谁。
If you could tell me who your three main references are in your profession.
si me podrías decir quiénes son tus tres referentes principales en tu profesión.
嗯，今天的团队很...不仅仅是因为不便
Well, the team today is very... not only because of the inconveniences
Bueno, el equipo hoy es muy... no solo por los inconvenientes
亚历克斯和尼科，但我们仍在评估我们将要玩的方式。
of Alex and Nico, but we are still evaluating the way we are going to play.
de Alex y de Nico, sino que todavía estamos evaluando la manera en que vamos a jugar.
也许我们可以做出一些改变。
Possibly we can make some changes.
posiblemente sí que podamos hacer algún cambio.
但今天我无法告诉你有多少，特别是今天的新闻发布会是比赛前一天。
But I couldn't tell you how many today, especially today the press conference is a day before the game.
pero no sabría decirte hoy cuántos, sobre todo hoy la rueda de prensa es un día todavía anterior al partido.
通常情况下。
Normally.
Normalmente.
因此，如果有任何变化，我们将等待。
So we will wait if there can be any changes.
Así que esperaremos si puede haber algún cambio.
那么技术层面上又如何呢？
And what about what on a technical level?
¿Y lo referente a que a nivel técnico?
您可以选择作为参考。
that you can choose as references.
que podés elegir como referentes.
嗯，我不能说。
Well, I couldn't say.
Bueno, no sabría decir.
我经历了很多，他们每次坐下来都会说同样的话。
I've had a lot and they all say the same thing every time they sit down.
Yo he tenido un montón y todos dicen lo mismo cada vez que se sientan.
我从好的和坏的事情中吸取了教训，我们都说同样的话。
I have learned from the good and the bad, we all say the same thing.
He aprendido de lo bueno y de lo malo, todos decimos lo mismo.
我请你考虑一下。
I ask you to think about it a little.
Te pido que lo pienses un poquito.
到最后甚至
in the end and even
al final e incluso
这就是为什么你要向那些你没有的人、那些不存在的人学习。
and that's why you learn from those you didn't have, from those who aren't there.
y por eso aprendes de los que no tuviste, de los que no están.
对今天的我来说，特别是当看到它时，一个参考......
For me today, a reference especially when seeing it...
Para mí hoy, referente sobre todo al verlo...
安切洛蒂在工作并倾听他的意见。
working and listening to him is Ancelotti.
trabajar y escucharlo es Ancelotti.
很多事情都和他一样，他对我来说就像一个男人......
Many things are the same as him and he seems like a guy to me...
Muchísimas cosas igual que él y me parece un tipo...
他正在走向得分，就这样，他已经创造了历史，而且......
that he is on his way to scoring, well that's it, he has already made history and that...
que va camino a marcar, bueno ya está, ya hizo historia y que...
他是一个让我倾听并在休息后感到认同的人。
He is a guy that I listen to and feel identified with after the rest.
Es un tipo que lo escucho y me siento identificado después del resto.
我所拥有的，何塞本人，D 中的伊鲁雷塔，他们的人......
the ones I have had, José, himself, Irureta in the D by people who...
los que he tenido, José, mismo, Irureta en el D por gente que...
这给我传递了很多东西，当我还是一名学生时，科尔多瓦教授给我传递了很多东西。
that has transmitted a lot to me, when I was a student, Professor Cordoba has transmitted a lot of things to me.
que me ha transmitido un montón, el profe Cordoba cuando estaba en estudiante me ha transmitido un montón de cosas.
他从所有技术人员那里学到东西，甚至从那些我们没有的技术人员那里学到东西。
He picks up things from all the technicians and even from those we haven't had.
va recatando cosas de todos los técnicos e incluso de los que no hemos tenido.
莱昂内尔在这里，巴勃罗·布鲁内托，我们为阿泰内而活。
Lionel here, Pablo Brunetto, we are live for Atene.
Lionel acá, Pablo Brunetto, estamos en vivo para Atene.
多年...
For many years...
Durante muchos años...
也许合乎逻辑，甚至很自然，有人谈论阿根廷队对梅西的依赖。
perhaps logically and even naturally, there was talk of a dependence on Messi in the Argentine team.
quizá de manera lógica y hasta natural, se habló de una dependencia de Messi en la selección argentina.
你认为此刻球队学会了在没有莱昂内尔的情况下比赛吗？
Do you think that at this moment the team learned to play without Lionel?
¿Crees que en este momento el equipo aprendió a jugar sin Lionel?
一支足球队很难不依赖利奥。
It is difficult for a football team not to be dependent on Leo.
Es difícil que un equipo de fútbol no tenga dependencia de Leo.
很多事情总是取决于他，因为你有一个独特的足球运动员，所以这甚至是合乎逻辑的。
A lot will always depend on him, because you have a unique footballer, so it is even logical.
Dependerá siempre de mucho de él, porque tenés a un futbolista único, entonces hasta es lógico.
但是，嘿，这支球队的好处是......
But hey, the good thing about this team...
Pero bueno, lo bueno que tiene este equipo...
我们对比赛的了解超出了场上人员的范围，并且口译员
that we have an idea of ​​the game beyond who is on the field and that the interpreters
que tenemos una idea de juego más allá de quien esté dentro de la cancha y que los intérpretes
它们可能有所不同，但或多或​​少它们都发挥相同的作用，所以这会有所帮助。
They can vary, but more or less they all play the same thing, so that helps.
pueden ir variando, pero más o menos juegan todos a la misma cosa, entonces eso ayuda.
但很明显，当Leo不在时......
But it is evident that when Leo is not there...
Pero es evidente que cuando no está Leo...
我们继续做同样的事情，但没有他那样的最后一击。
We continue doing the same thing but without that final touch that he has.
Seguimos haciendo lo mismo pero sin ese toque final que él tiene.
但是嘿，团队...
but hey, the team...
pero bueno, el equipo...
你的足球运动员的素质或者你的足球运动员的踢球方式是......
The quality of your footballer or the way your footballer plays is...
la calidad de su futbolista o la manera de jugar su futbolista es...
场上的所有位置都是相似的，无论场上是谁，每个人都知道自己必须做什么。
It is similar in all positions on the field and everyone knows what they have to do regardless of who is on the field.
es similar en todos los puestos de la cancha y todos saben lo que tienen que hacer más allá de quienes estén dentro de la cancha.
你好吗？
How are you doing?
¿Cómo andás?
关于周二比赛的两个问题。
Two questions in reference to Tuesday's game.
Dos preguntas en referencia al partido del martes.
第一，如果有条件，如果热，如果……
The first, if the conditions, if the heat, if...
La primera, si las condiciones, si el calor, si...
即将进行的比赛时间很早，也许不那么平常。
the time of the game that is going to be played, which is very early, perhaps not so usual.
el momento del partido que se va a jugar que es muy temprano, quizás no tan habitual.
在组建团队时你会考虑到这一点，否则它不会改变你。
You take it into account when putting together the team, or it doesn't change you.
lo tenés en cuenta a la hora de armar el equipo, o eso no te cambia.
我不会问你哥伦比亚队通过死球进了多少球，我想你已经知道了，但如果他们有的话......
I'm not going to ask you how many goals Colombia scored from dead balls, I imagine you already know, but if they have any...
no te voy a preguntar cuántos goles hizo Colombia de pelota parada, imagino que ya lo sabes, pero si tienen alguna...
由于哥伦比亚的管理方式，他们是否会以不同的方式受到保护？
Are they going to be protected in a different way because of how Colombia is managed?
¿se van a resguardar de una manera distinta por cómo se maneja Colombia?
他在美洲杯上变得更强。
He has become strong in the Copa América.
Se ha hecho fuerte en la Copa América.
有一天，他用定位球扳平了秘鲁队。
The other day he tied Peru with a set piece.
El otro día empató a Perú de pelota parada.
由于哥伦比亚在这方面变得越来越强大，您是否采取了任何特殊的预防措施？
Do you take any special precautions because of how Colombia is becoming stronger in that sense?
¿tomas algún resguardo en especial por cómo Colombia se hace fuerte en ese sentido?
嗯，日程安排的问题对我们俩来说都是一样的，前几天我说……
Well, the issue of the schedule is the same for both of us, when the other day I said...
Bueno, el tema del horario es para los dos igual, yo cuando el otro día dije...
最终非常困难的是我们双方，我说的是
What is very difficult in the end is for both of us, what I say is
lo que es muy difícil al final es para los dos lo que digo es
为了足球运动员的舒适度，为了景观。
for the comfort of the footballer, for the spectacle.
por la comodidad del futbolista, por el espectáculo.
舒服，我并不是说哪个有优势，但确实是……
comfortable, I'm not saying that one or the other has an advantage, but it is true that it is...
cómodo, no digo que tenga ventaja uno u otro, pero si es verdad que es...
时间表对演出没有帮助。
The schedule doesn't help the show.
el horario no ayuda al espectáculo.
是的，我们拿出来的装备都会根据热量来的吧？
Yes, the equipment we take out will be based on the heat, right?
Si el equipo que saquemos será en función del calor, no?
我们派出的球队是基于以最好的方式面对比赛，就像我们一直所做的那样。
The team we put out was based on facing the game, as we always did, in the best way.
El equipo que saquemos era en función de afrontar el partido, como siempre hicimos, de la mejor manera.
关于停球的事情，好吧，我们总是有办法防守而不是
And the thing about the stopped ball, well, we always have a way of defending and not
y lo de la pelota parada bueno siempre nosotros tenemos una manera de defender y no
我们总是看到竞争对手，我们进行分析，但不......
We always see the rivals, we analyze and don't...
Siempre vemos a los rivales, analizamos y no...
我们不会改变我们的防守方式。
We are not going to change our way of defending.
No vamos a cambiar nuestra manera de defender.
确实，有时候你必须改变一些球员的位置......
It is true that there are times when you have to change the position of some players to...
Es verdad que hay veces que tenés que cambiar de posición algunos jugadores para...
防守定位球，这就是我们在不同比赛中所做的。
to defend set pieces and that is what we do in different games.
para defender las pelotas paradas y eso es lo que hacemos en diferentes partidos.
但很明显，这是他们拥有的武器，我们必须小心。
but it is evident that it is a weapon that they have and we must be careful.
pero es evidente que es un arma que tienen ellos y hay que tener cuidado.
尼科·贝尔纳多 (Nico Bernardo)，《Le》报纸
Nico Bernardo, for the newspaper Le.
Nico Bernardo, para el diario Le.
这还没有列入议程，但我想这可能会在明年举行，也就是对阵西班牙的决赛。
It is not on the agenda yet, but I imagine that it may be within what will be next year, which is the very final against Spain.
No está en agenda todavía, pero imagino que dentro de lo que será el año que viene puede llegar a estar, que es la finalísima contra España.
我想问你...
I wanted to ask you...
Quería preguntarte...
对于你来说，你承认你也是西班牙的粉丝，尤其是路易斯·德拉富恩特，
For you, who confessed that you are also a bit of a fan of Spain, especially for Luis de la Fuente,
para vos, que te confesaste un poco también hincha de España, sobre todo por Luis de la Fuente,
如果你对那场比赛有期待，你想象什么，它会变成什么，
If you have expectations for that match, what do you imagine, what it can become,
Si tenés expectativas por ese partido, qué imaginás, qué puede llegar a ser,
如果您希望它尽快发生。
and if you intend for it to happen as quickly as possible.
y si tenés intenciones de que se dé lo más rápido posible.
原则上我不知道，我不知道它是否会播放，据我所知，明年肯定会很困难。
In principle I don't know, I don't know if it will be played, next year will surely be difficult from what I have been told.
En principio no sé, no sé si se va a jugar, el año que viene seguramente sea difícil por lo que me han comentado.
日期，特别是西班牙，其世界杯资格赛要到 11 月才能进行。
of the dates, especially that of Spain, which has World Cup qualification until November.
de las fechas, sobre todo que tiene España, que tiene clasificación del Mundial hasta noviembre.
我认为明年不可行，我们会看看他们是否会考虑。
I don't see it being feasible next year, we'll see if they look.
no lo veo factible el año que viene, ya se verá si buscan.
差距是因为在这些事情中你突然必须在一场又一场比赛的中间进行比赛，但我不认为这一点。
a gap because in these things you suddenly have to go play in the middle of one game and another, but I don't see it.
un hueco porque en estas cosas después de repente tienes que ir a jugar en medio de un partido y otro, pero no la veo.
而且距离很远，我并没有考虑到这一点，我只有这些信息，我们会看到什么
and it is very far away, I am not with that in mind, I only have that information and we will see what
y queda lejísimo no estoy con eso en la cabeza sólo tengo esa información y ya veremos qué
让它发生吧。
let it happen.
que suceda.
这些天是您首次担任阿根廷国家队教练以来的六周年纪念日。
These days marked 6 years since your debut in the Argentine national team as a coach.
En estos días se cumplieron 6 años de tu debut en la selección argentina como entrenador.
你还记得那一天以及你职业生涯中最重要的时刻吗？
What do you remember about that day and the most important moments of your career?
¿Qué recordás de aquel día y los momentos más importantes de tu carrera?
如果你能告诉我们，你觉得怎么样？
If you can tell us, right? What do you think?
si podés contarnos, ¿no?, ¿cuáles te parecen?
我记得我们开始训练的前一周我们在洛杉矶训练。
I remember the week before we started training that we trained in Los Angeles.
Recuerdo la semana previa empezar a entrenar que entrenamos en Los Ángeles.
好吧，一切都很新，有一些不匹配，因为逻辑上
Well, everything is very new, with some mismatches because logically
Bueno, todo muy nuevo, con algunos desajustes porque lógicamente
我们本来就不是...
We were not...
Nosotros no estábamos...
他们已经习惯了球员的到来，他们有时到达，有时晚一点，而且很好，并与他们一起参加训练课程。
They are used to the arrival of players, who arrive at one time or another, one later and good and taking the training sessions with
están acostumbrados a la llegada de jugadores, que llegan a un horario u otro, uno más tarde y bueno y sacando los entrenamientos con
我们可以，但总是带着微笑，总是带着喜悦。
We could, but always with a smile, always with joy.
podíamos, pero siempre con una sonrisa, siempre con alegría.
所有这些不平衡不仅可能存在于我们这边，也可能存在于我们这边
and all those imbalances that could exist not only on our side but also
y todos esos desajustes que podía haber no sólo del lado nuestro sino que
对于从未去过那里的新玩家，我们自然而然地让他们知道这是
new players who had never been there, we take it naturally so that they know it was
jugadores nuevos que nunca habían estado lo tomamos con naturalidad que ellos sepan que era
每个人都面带微笑，焕然一新
that everyone was practically new and good with a smile
que todo el mundo era nuevo prácticamente y bueno con una sonrisa
以及最重要的三个时刻
and the three most moments
y los tres momentos más
世界杯肯定是快乐且肯定的。
happily and surely the World Cup.
feliz y seguramente la Copa del Mundo.
决赛前的两场美洲杯无疑是独一无二的时刻。
and the two Copa América ahead of the very final are undoubtedly unique moments.
y las dos Copa América por delante de la finalísima sin duda son momentos únicos.
我们不会忘记它。
And we are not going to forget it.
Y no lo vamos a olvidar.
下周二您将达到 79 场比赛的新纪录。
Next Tuesday you will reach a new record of 79 games.
El próximo martes vas a alcanzar un nuevo récord de 79 partidos.
梅诺蒂和比拉尔多答应了。
Menotti and Bilardo complied.
cumplieron Menotti y Bilardo.
我的意思是，这项新成就占据了你的大脑超过四个......
I mean, that new achievement occupies your mind beyond four...
Digo, te ocupa en tu cabeza ese nuevo logro más allá de las cuatro...
你跑了几圈，你只是在谈论温度，或者他们问你温度。
laps you took and you were just talking about the temperature or they asked you about the temperature.
vueltas que diste y recién hablabas de la temperatura o te consultaban de la temperatura.
如果您担心并担心巴兰基亚将存在的不利环境。
If you are worried and worried about the adverse context that will exist in Barranquilla.
si te preocupa y preocupa también el contexto adverso que va a haber en Barranquilla.
谢谢。
Gracias.
嗯，首先尼科在车里告诉我他正在玩这些游戏。
Well, first Nico told me in the car now that he was playing those games.
Bueno, primero me dijo Nico en el auto ahora que cumplía esos partidos.
我不喜欢统计数据。
I am not a fan of statistics.
No soy partidario de las estadísticas.
好吧，很高兴，因为我们达到了一个有趣的数字，但最终......
And well, happy, because we reached an interesting number, but in the end...
Y bueno, contento, porque llegar a un número interesante, pero al final...
它们只是数字，它会留在那里。
They are just numbers and it will stay there.
son sólo números y quedará ahí.
对我来说，上下文似乎是正常的上下文。
And the context seems like a normal context to me.
Y el contexto me parece un contexto normal.
这种事总是会发生，然后你在街上遇到哥伦比亚人......
This always happens, then you meet Colombians on the street and...
Esto pasa siempre, después con los colombianos te encuentras por la calle y...
你和一切都相处得很好，我有哥伦比亚朋友，他们都是不可思议的人
and you get along with everything well and I have Colombian friends and they are incredible people
y te llevas con todo recontra bien y tengo amigos colombianos y son gente increíble
但在球场上他们希望自己的球队获胜
but on the field they want their team to win
pero adentro de la cancha quieren que gane su equipo
这很正常。
It's normal.
Es normal.
我们从未遇到过除此之外的任何事情，所以我认为这很正常。
We never met anything beyond that, so I see it as normal.
Nunca nos encontramos algo más allá de eso, así que lo veo normal.
他们对我们来说是非常亲爱的人。
They are very dear people to us.
Son gente muy querida por nosotros.
我认为反之亦然，当比赛开始时他们会这样做
and I think vice versa then well and when the game is played they do
y creo que viceversa entonces bueno y cuando se juega el partido hacen
他们竭尽全力去赢得胜利，在我看来
everything they can to win and it seems to me
todo lo que puedan para ganar y me parece
公平，我认为他们甚至没有认为他们做得太过分，因为他们一直对我们很好。
fair and I think it's not even thinking that they go too far because they have always treated us well.
justo y creo que ni siquiera es pensar que se pasan porque siempre nos han tratado bien.
韦纳多广播电台的莱昂内尔、马克西和大卫·阿莱莫斯。
Leonel, Maxi and David Alemos for Radio Ciudad Venado.
Leonel, Maxi y David Alemos para Radio Ciudad Venado.
阿根廷队的开局相当具有爆炸性。
Argentina had a pretty explosive start.
Argentina tuvo un comienzo bastante explosivo.
预选赛中，除了与乌拉圭的比赛，这场比赛相当复杂。
in the qualifiers, except for the match with Uruguay, which was quite complex.
en las eliminatorias, salvo el partido con Uruguay que fue bastante complejo ese encuentro.
他取得了很多胜利，只有一场失败，他对其他人产生了很大的影响。
He had many victories and only one defeat, he made a big difference to the rest.
cosechó muchos triunfos y una sola derrota, le sacó mucha diferencia al resto.
预选赛的难度是否仍超出阿根廷队的水平？
Are the qualifiers still difficult beyond the level that Argentina is having?
¿Sigue siendo difícil las eliminatorias más allá del nivel que está teniendo Argentina?
是的，是的，这很困难，除了你必须看到很多背景如何......
Yes, yes, it is difficult, apart from the fact that you have to see a lot of the context of how...
Sí, sí, es difícil, aparte que hay que ver mucho el contexto de cómo...
我们能够赢得那些比赛。
We were able to win those games.
pudimos ganar esos partidos.
对于我们中的一些人来说，我们显然赢了，而对于其他人来说，情况很复杂。
For some of us we clearly won, for others it was complicated.
A algunos lo ganamos claramente, a otros se nos complicaron.
当你相信自己时，那一刻可能会更加……我不知道……
and when you trust yourself, the moment may be more... I don't know...
y cuando te confías, el momento a lo mejor más... no sé...
我记得世界杯之前，我们的最佳时刻，阿拉伯抓住了我们并击败了我们。
I remember before the World Cup, our best moment, Arabia caught us and beat us.
Me acuerdo de antes del Mundial, el mejor momento nuestro, nos agarró Arabia y nos ganó.
在我看来，这种情况随时可能发生，重要的是恢复。
It seems to me that it can happen at any time and the important thing is to recover.
Me parece que en cualquier momento puede pasar y lo importante es reponerse.
我认为水平是均匀的。
I think the level is even.
Creo que el nivel es parejo.
我们现在看到了秘鲁-哥伦比亚。
We now saw Peru-Colombia.
Vimos ahora Perú-Colombia.
他需要获得他本可以赢得的积分，并且在积分榜上垫底或垫底。
He was in need of points that he could have earned and was last or is last in the standings.
estaba necesitado de puntos que pudo ganar y era último o es último en la clasificación.
所以这给人一种一切都是平等的基调。
So that gives the tone that everything is even.
Entonces eso da la pauta de que está todo parejo.
我们已经提出了很好的观点，我认为我们做得很好，但没有必要混淆。
We have made good points and I think we are doing well, but there is no need to confuse.
Hemos hecho buenos puntos y creo que estamos bien, pero no hay que confundir.
莱昂内尔是足球无线电木材温度计的作者。
Leonell here, the author of the football radio thermometer for wood.
Leonell acá, el autorado de los para madero radio termómetro futbolero.
您如何看待这次入选国家队的新球员的适应情况？
How did you see the adaptation of the new kids who came in this call for the national team?
¿Cómo viste la adaptación de los chicos nuevos que vinieron en esta convocatoria para la selección?
以及是否有可能有人在下一场对阵哥伦比亚的比赛中首次亮相。
and if there is the possibility that someone could debut in this next match with Colombia.
y si hay la posibilidad de que alguno pueda debutar en este próximo partido con Colombia.
好吧，好吧，他们是这样的人……
Well, well, they are guys who...
Bueno, bien, son chicos que...
我们大多数人都认识他，其他人我们不认识，但他们都在青年队。
Most of us knew him, others we hadn't had but they had been in the youth teams.
La mayoría lo conocíamos, a otros no lo habíamos tenido nosotros pero habían estado en las juveniles.
他们年轻时也非常了解彼此。
They know each other very well as youths as well.
Se conocen muy bien de juveniles también.
也许我们可以看到某个男孩，是的，当然......
and possibly we can see some boy, yes, surely...
y posiblemente podamos ver a algún chico, sí, seguramente...
这在很大程度上取决于比赛的进展情况，这就是他们的目的，贡献自己的力量。
It will depend a lot on the game, how it goes and that's what they are there for, to contribute their own.
Dependerá mucho del partido, de cómo se dé y para eso están, para aportar lo suyo.
如果我们觉得他们玩方便的话。
if we think it is convenient for them to play.
si creemos conveniente que puedan jugar.
莱昂内尔，伊克尔·穆纳因本周抵达圣洛伦索是阿根廷足球界的事情吗？
Leonel, did the arrival of Iker Muñaín to San Lorenzo take place this week in Argentine football?
Leonel, ¿se dio esta semana la llegada al fútbol argentino de Iker Muñaín a San Lorenzo?
如果您对一位对西班牙如此了解的西班牙人来到阿根廷感到惊讶，是什么让您感到惊讶？
What generates you and if you were surprised that a Spaniard, who knows so much about Spain, arrives here in Argentina?
¿Qué te genera y si te sorprendió que un español, vos conociendo tanto España, llegue aquí a la Argentina?
令人惊讶，我不知道是否值得惊讶，但确实，他是一位表现仍然不错的球员。
Surprising, I don't know whether to surprise, but it is true that he is a player who is still doing well.
Sorprender, no sé si sorprender, pero sí es verdad que es un jugador que todavía está bien.
它已经生效，可以为圣洛伦索带来很多。
It is in force, it can give a lot to San Lorenzo.
Está vigente, le puede dar bastante a San Lorenzo.
在他在西班牙踢球的这些年里，他一直是一个不同的足球运动员，所以
In the years that he has played in Spain he has always been a different footballer and so
en los años que ha jugado en España siempre ha sido un futbolista diferente y por lo que
我知道您对阿根廷足球充满热情。
I understand that you are passionate about Argentine soccer.
Entiendo que le apasiona el fútbol argentino.
我希望一切顺利，为其他想要来的孩子打开大门。
And I hope it goes well so that it can open the door for other kids who want to come.
Y ojalá le vaya bien para que pueda abrir puerta a otros chicos que quieran venir.
对我来说这似乎很野蛮。
It seems barbaric to me.
Me parece bárbaro.
我们不仅去那里，他们也来这里。
Not only do we go there, but they come here.
No solo que vayamos nosotros para allá, sino que vengan ellos para acá.
如果踢得好的话对足球有好处
It would be good for football if it does well
sería bueno para el fútbol que le vaya bien
他对我们的足球有着良好的印象。
and that he has a good image of our football.
y que él tenga una buena imagen de nuestro fútbol.
目前，事实是，他选择来阿根廷踢球是值得赞赏的，因为他是一名足球运动员，
For now, the truth is that it is appreciated that he has chosen to come to play in Argentina because he is a footballer who
Por lo pronto la verdad que es de agradecer que haya elegido venir a jugar a Argentina porque es un futbolista que
我认为这仍然有效。
which I think is still valid.
que creo que todavía está vigente.
谢谢教练。
Thanks coach.
Gracias entrenador.
祝大家周日好。
Good Sunday to everyone.
Buen domingo para todos.